

AHMAD SYAHIR BIN ZURAIDIN

★ Kajang, Selangor, Malaysia
 +6016-9797 688
 syahir.zuraidin@gmail.com
 linkedin.com/in/syahir21

github.com/syah1r

syah1r.github.io/my-portfolio/

PROFILE

Possess 4 years of programming experience across multiple industries including oil & gas and financial services, handling projects valued up to RM10mil. Proficient in data management, business analytics and process automation using tools such as Python, SQL, Excel VBA, SAS and Power BI. Familiar with git, agile development, statistical analysis, and object-oriented programming.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programmer Analyst Jan 2023 – Present

NMG Consulting Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Performed data cleansing, transformation, analysis, and visualization in SAS.
- Utilized SQL to query and extract data from multiple tables and databases using JOIN and UNION statements.
- Created Python and Excel VBA scripts to automate ad-hoc repetitive tasks which help reduce processing time by 50%.
 Automation features include data extraction, cleaning, quality assessment, data aggregation from multiple databases and automated visualization export to PowerPoint.
- Work closely with clients to determine the best metrics to be displayed on final product.
- Used Power Query to explore and transform datasets and create dashboards in Power Bl.

Analyst May 2021 – May 2022

MMC Oil & Gas Engineering

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Compile reports and prepare PowerPoint presentation deck for customers.
- Communicate with client and business analysts to verify technical, non-technical requirements and deliverables.
- Built an automation tool using VBA macro and Python to compute commercial variables and costs.

Project Engineer Mar 2019 – May 2021

Well Experts Services

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Created 10+ reports using Power BI to help clients with insights and comparison.
- Transformed and processed client's data by using DAX and Excel to ensure data completeness and validity.
- Participated in techno-commercial discussion between internal team and client to ensure scope of work compliance, timely project delivery and costs are within budget.

PROJECTS

Library Management System

Apr 2023

• Developed a system in C# (.NET) to manage books and library operations with CRUD functionality, login authentication, book tracking, lending and return dates, and search and filter options. Integrated with MySQL database for data storage and performed unit testing using NUnit.

Statistical Analysis of Hospitality Industry Dataset

Jul 2022

- Aggregated and visualized data by using Python (pandas, seaborn, plotly, matplotlib and wordcloud) to compile a
 professional report.
- Performed web scraping (API), outlier detection, trend and regression analysis using various modelling techniques.

EDUCATION

MSc in Software Engineering

Aug 2021 - Present

Asia Pacific University

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

• CGPA: 3.71/4.00

BEng (Honors) in Petroleum Engineering

Jan 2015 - Jan 2019

University Technology PETRONAS

Perak, Malaysia

• CGPA: 3.60/4.00

Cambridge IGCSE (O-Level)

Jan 2009 - Jan 2014

Qatar International School

Doha, Qatar

• Grade: 4A*, 2A, 2B

CERTIFICATIONS

SAS Macro Programming - Advanced

Feb 2023

Udemy

• Exposure to macro variables and macro functions to create efficient SAS codes.

Power BI Feb 2023

SEIDOR Analytics

• Exposure to power query, DAX, data modelling, visualization, and dashboard publishing in Power BI.

Agile Software Development

Feb 2022

LinkedIn

• Exposure to SDLC and agile methodologies such as scrum, extreme programming, and Kanban.

Excel/VBA for Creative Problem-Solving

Apr 2021

Coursera

• Exposure to VBA scripting, macros and Excel functions for automation and analysis.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (React)

• Python (Pandas, NumPy)

Azure DevOps

• HTML

• C++

Power BI

CSSSQL (MSSQL Server, MySQL)

• C# (.NET Framework)

VBA

• Microsoft Office Suite

SAS